# Andrés Sánchez Marín

15 June 1997 | Madrid, Spain andres.sanchez@imdea.org | andsanmar.github.io

## **AREAS OF INTEREST**

My research fields of interest are the Formal Methods, Systems (OS, databases and Security & Privacy), Programming Languages & Paradigms (specially on functional and low level paradigms), Software Optimization, Algorithms and Data Structures, Hardware Architecture and Theoretical Fundations of Computer Science. In resume, I'm interested in all the things that involve the development of reliable and optimized software, also finding weaknesses of bad implementations.

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

IMDEA Software Institute

Madrid, Spain

Research Internship

Sep 2018 - present

Survey of existing Spectre exploits and existing proposals for countermeasures. Analysis of these countermeasures w.r.t. speculative noninterference. Implementation of a tool for automatically detecting speculative leaks

Distributed Systems Laboratory at UPM

Madrid, Spain

Internship

Sep 2017 - Dec 2017

Doing test applications over a NoSQL distributed database. Designing and implementing a feature over a Elastic Complex Event Processing for Static and Streaming Data

Cisco, NBA Madrid, Spain

#### **NBA NetAcad Dream Team member**

Oct 2016

On the NBA Global Games (Madrid). Learning how to do the network infrastructure for the event. Also, helping installing it

#### **EDUCATION**

Universidad Politécnica de Madrid

Madrid, Spain 2015 - 2019

### **Bachelor of Science in Mathematics and Computing**

Member of ACM UPM chapter

**SKILLS** 

LANGUAGES Spanish (mother tongue)

English (fluent) - 90 TOEFL iBT

PROGRAMMING Haskell, Linux, Prolog, C, Git

Assembly, LATEX, Rust, Python

ACHIEVEMENTS 8 honors in various subjects on Bachelor's degree

OTHERS CCNA 1 & 2

Free Time Monitor Certification.

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE Sumac Wasi "Santo Tomás de Aquino" enhancement project during 2018

summer as a collaborator, also doing recreational and learning activities with

a group of 40 kids on a marginal Arequipa (Perú) area.